

### **ABOUT ME**

Motivated AI researcher with a focus on Explainable AI. Current Research Assistant at Epley Lab. Graduated with an M.S. in Applied Data Science at the University of Chicago with a 4.0 GPA. Earned bachelor's degrees in Economics, Finance, and History as a triple major at The Ohio State University. Experienced in teaching roles across STEM fields. Recipient of the Pace Setters Award.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

SCENE: EVALUATING EXPLAINABLE AI TECHNIQUES USING SOFT COUNTERFACTUALS UNDER REVIEW

AUG 2024

#### SKILLS

**EXPLAINABLE AI TECHNIQUES** 

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

MACHINE LEARNING FRAMEWORKS

NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING

CAUSAL INFERENCE

BAYESIAN METHODS

#### LINK

#### Personal Website:

https://haoranzhengraul.github.io/

# HAORAN Zheng

512 N McClurg Ct, Chicago, IL 60611, United States of America

**513-909-5366** 

xaulzhenghaoran@gmail.com

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### EPLEY LAB

Sep 2024 - Present

#### Research Assistant

 Collaborated closely with Dr. Nicholas Epley and Yale scholar Yin Li on "The Multicultural Study," focusing on cross-cultural perceptions of beliefs and preferences.

### MINDWORKS LAB

Apr 2024 - Present

#### Research Specialist

- Co-manage studies and collect data for renowned scholars like Dr. Nicholas Epley and Dr. Sarah Sebo.
- · Literature review.
- Collaborated with the University of Chicago Human-Robot Interaction Lab. Investigated the impact of personality alignment between humans and robots on the effectiveness of positive psychology exercises.

# DR. CHRISTOPHER REED

Sep 2024 - Present

#### Research Assistant

- Applied modern NLP techniques and the SCENE method to traditional History research.
- Aim to identify the significance of previously unseen documents.

# THE OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY

Feb 2021 - May 2022

#### Teaching Assistant

- Conducted two weekly recitations for 65 students each, focusing on statistical concepts and analytic tools like R.
- Made customized review notes and visual aids to all 920 students that were enrolled.

# **EDUCATION**

# THE UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO

Chicago, IL 2024

### Master of Science in Applied Data Science

- Thesis: "Demystifying the Black Box: An Empirical Evaluation of Explainable Al Techniques in NLP Tasks".
- Advisor: Dr. Utku Pamuksuz.
- Notable Coursework: Bayesian Methods, Generative Al Principles, Advanced Linear Algebra for ML.

# THE OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY

Columbus, OH 2022

# Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

- Triple major in Economics, Finance, and History.
- Majors' GPAs: Economics (3.9/4.0), Finance (3.8/4.0), History (3.8/4.0).